A Guide to the Bishop Ireton High School Collection, 2004-2009
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Bishop Ireton High School Collection, 2004-2009
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 11-16
.5 linear feet
The Bishop Ireton High School Collection consists of .5 linear feet and spans the years 2004-2009 and consists of student newspapers, school calendars, newsletters, student directories, programs, tickets, newspaper clippings, and a prom invitation. Subjects include student life and extracurricular activities at Bishop Ireton High School; private education in Alexandria, Virginia; and the Diocese of Arlington.
Barbuschak, Chris
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Collection assembled and donated by Chris Barbuschak in December 2015.
Historical and Biographical Information
The Oblates of St. Frances DeSales founded Bishop Ireton High School in Alexandria, Virginia in 1964. The Oblates named the school after Peter Leo Ireton, bishop of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Arlington from 1945 to 1958. Initially an all-boys high school, Bishop Ireton became co-ed with the closing of nearby St. Mary’s Academy in 1990. The original school building located at 201 Cambridge Road has expanded over the years and is now under the Diocese of Arlington’s control after the Oblates left the school in 2008.
Scope and Content
Series 1: School Publications, 2004-2007, Box 1
This series contains student newspapers, school calendars, newsletters, and student directories. Subjects include The BI Word, The Cardinal Connection and Post-Flight Alumni Newsletter.
Series 2: Programs, 2004-2008, Box 1
This series consists of programs from various school happenings including sporting events, concerts, theatre performances, masses, and graduation.
Series 3: Ephemera, 2006-2009, Box 1
This series contains news clippings, a graduation ticket, and a prom invitation. Newspaper clipping subjects include Taylor Swift’s 2009 concert at the school, the Oblates’ 2008 departure, and Ireton’s football team.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Bishop Ireton High School (Alexandria, Va.) - Student life; Private schools - Virginia - Alexandria; Roman Catholic Diocese of Arlington
Container List
- Series 1: School Publications, 2004-2007
  - The BI Word, 2005 October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The BI Word, 2005 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The BI Word [partial], 2006 February (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The BI Word, 2006 September/October (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The BI Word, 2006 October/November (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The BI Word, 2006 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The BI Word, 2007 April (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, 2004 October (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, 2005 February (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, 2005 April (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, 2005 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, 2006 January (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, 2006 June (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Cardinal Connection Bulletin, Autumn 2007, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Post-Flight Alumni Newsletter, Summer 2005, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Post-Flight Alumni Newsletter, Spring 2006, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - School Calendar, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - School Calendar, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - School Calendar, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Student Directory, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Student Directory, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series 2: Programs, 2004-2008
  - Bishop Ireton Cardinals 2004 Fall Sports Program, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Program, Mass of the Holy Spirit, 2004 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Program, United States Navy Band In Concert at Garwood Whaley Auditorium, 2004 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Program and ticket, South Pacific play, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Program, Thirty-First Annual Combined Concert of Music for Wind and Percussion Instruments featuring the United States Navy Band and the Bishop Ireton Symphonic Wind Ensemble, 2005 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Program, Zombie Prom play, 2005 November (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Program, All Saints Day Liturgy, 2005 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Program, Thirty-Second Annual Combined Concert of Music for Wind and Percussion Instruments featuring Paragon Brass and the Bishop Ireton Symphonic Wind Ensemble, 2006 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Program, Mass of the Holy Spirit, 2006 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Program and ticket, Ireton Cardinals vs. Riverdale Baptist Crusaders, 2006 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Program, Class of 2008 Junior Ring Mass, 2006 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Program and ticket, Commencement Exercises, 2008 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Series 3: Ephemera, 2006-2009
  - Graduation Ticket, 2006 May 31 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Invitation, 2008 Junior-Senior Prom, 2008 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous news clippings, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 36)